How do we do writes to this memory?
Obviously, we need to change one of the
cells. How do we do that? We use the row
address to select the row of the cell.
But we can only select a whole row of
cells. We cannot just select an
individual cell. So, if this is bit
number seven in our 32-bit word, we
select the address of the word and then
we want to supply a bit here. Let's say
A1 to be written here. So, how do we do
that? because we can only select a whole
row. Once we select the row, all of the
cells get connected to the bit lines. We
can maybe drive the bit line for this
one to write the one. But that would
lose us these bits. So the way the write
needs to happen is we use the row
address, select the row, read out these
bits, the sense
amplifies them, and we latch them into
the row buffer. Now we write this bit to
the row buffer at this position. And now
we write the whole thing back into the
cells. The cells lost their values when
we did the read anyway. We would have to
write the values back. Anyway, before we
do that, we make all the writes that we
want to that row and then send them
back. So that when we are writing, we
end up writing one one and this bit is
changed to one. So a write in DM is also
a read and then write operation.